Now let's take a look at how to use the animation character in M.I.E. to create a costume animation.
First, in M.I.E. prepare the joint key needle.
Then select the body grid for the Alambic file.
You can also use other formats, such as FBX and PC2, but in this video, we will show you how to use Alambic.
After selecting the body, save the animation file.
Open the costume file in Marvelous Designer.
Then import the Alambic file that you saved from M.I.E.
Then adjust the surface of the model.
The surface diameter determines the distance between the body grid and the costume in the simulation process.
Since the character we use in this video is much smaller than the normal adult, we will reduce the surface diameter to default.
Activate the simulation or press the control key to check if the costume is correctly worn on the body.
After pausing the simulation, click the record button to start the animation operation and record the animation at the same time.
After the animation is completed, the costume with the animation will be exported to M.I.E.
I will export the costume animation to the Alambic file, which is the most commonly used file type.
But please note that you can also use other formats, such as PCO and MC.
For example, if you need to merge the connection point, please select the merge option.
In addition, please select the unified UV coordinates.
To export the UV created by you in Marvelous Designer.
If you don't need to prepare the pattern, you can cancel it in the following options box.
I will choose 0mm as the unit in the ratio because it is the same unit as we used when exporting.
Then select the confirm button.
Now let's import the costume file to M.I.E.
You can press cache to save.
Alambic cache Alambic to save.
Go to Alambic to find and select the costume file.
Now you can start animation costumes and work in M.I.E.